There's a fire in the sky in the morning
早上天上有火
when the Sun is a crimson dawning..
当太阳是深红色的破晓时..
And the earth is glowing like a burning ember.
地球像燃烧的余烬一样发光。
Who's land is this? This is my land.
这是谁的土地？ 这是我的土地。
See the shadow of the eagle in the sunrise
日出时见鹰影
hear the music of the children
听孩子们的音乐
in the moon rise feel the power of the lion
在月亮升起时感受狮子的力量
when he roars like thunder
当他如雷霆般咆哮时
calling who's land is this? This is my land.
呼唤谁是土地这是？ 这是我的土地。
Who's land is this? This is my land.
这是谁的土地？ 这是我的土地。
Okay Pat, hello girl.. O my, what are you doing?
好的，帕特，你好女孩.. 天哪，你在做什么？
What's that rogue Togar doing here?
那个流氓托加尔在这里做什么？
God Togar, why today of all days.
God Togar，为什么是今天。
Okay, come on let's play chase.
好了，来玩追剧吧。
The closer we get, the more excited I get.
我们越接近，我就越兴奋。
It should be great to see him after three years.
三年后能见到他应该是件好事。
Yeah, I couldn't believe how fast he split for Africa after he got his grant.
是的，我简直不敢相信他在获得资助后为非洲分道扬镳的速度如此之快。
And the zoo let him take the little cubs he raised.
动物园让他带走他养的小崽子。
You'd think he'd take the kids he raised!
你会认为他会带走他抚养的孩子！
Well he was going to send for us but he said it was too dangerous.
好吧，他打算派人来接我们，但他说这太危险了。
He certainly didn't leave because he didn't love us.
他当然没有离开，因为他不爱我们。
You know how depressed he used to get..
你知道他过去有多沮丧..
with his cats being kept in cages all the time.
他的猫一直被关在笼子里。
- I wonder where he is.. - Why don't we find our own way there?
- 我想知道他在哪里.. - 我们为什么不去那里找自己的路呢？
- You're joking! - Where could he be?
- 你开玩笑吧！  - 他会在哪里？
Why, you guys wait till my family get here tonight. Are they gonna love you!
为什么，你们等我家人今晚来。 他们会爱你吗！
- Sorry Hank. - And I thought you came to help me.
- 对不起汉克。  - 我还以为你是来帮我的。
I did. I come to speak for you with that committee..
我做到了。 我来和那个委员会代表你说话..
And take you to pick up your family.
并带你去接你的家人。
Well, come on shore awhile.
嗯，上岸一会儿。
Are you crazy? The committee is on their way here to review your grant.
你疯了？ 委员会正在前往审查您的赠款。
Monster..
怪物..
Come on. You gotta help me clean the house.
来吧。 你得帮我打扫房子。
Not today! Today doesn't seem like a good date coming.
今天不行！ 今天似乎不是一个好的约会。
Hey, where you going?
嘿，你要去哪里？
Not my jacket!
不是我的夹克！
Throw it here! Come on over here.
扔这里！ 过来这边。
- Stay there. - How's she's doing?
- 留在这。  - 她好吗？
This is a madhouse.
这是一个疯人院。
No, it's just like life you get the funny with the tragic.
不，这就像生活一样，您会因悲剧而变得有趣。
Just with them you get the gentle and the ferocious too.
和他们在一起，你也会变得温柔和凶猛。
Be careful of the bad and enjoy the good.
提防坏的，享受好的。
You aren't careful enough.
你不够小心。
For my studies I have to get as close to them as possible.
为了我的学习，我必须尽可能接近他们。
No actually, the closer you get to them
不，实际上，你离他们越近
the more they like you, the safer you'd be.
他们越喜欢你，你就越安全。
- But look, it's going to jump on us! - Oh no no no..
- 但是看，它会跳到我们身上！  - 哦不不不..
They're just playing...
他们只是在玩...
They like to play the cat and mouse game.
他们喜欢玩猫捉老鼠的游戏。
Here, I'll cover you O, big Joe...
在这里，我会掩护你哦，大乔……
No, if you just look at them...
不，如果你只是看着他们......
- Or you run at them, roar - O god... no look
- 或者你跑向他们，吼叫 - 哦上帝...别看
What? Na-aah-ah, you leave him alone!
什么？ 啊啊啊啊，你别管他了！
Oh, that's Johnny lion. You never have to worry about John.
哦，那是约翰尼狮子。 你永远不必担心约翰。
Are you scaring him?
你在吓唬他吗？
You know you're gotta watch out for Mark...
你知道你得小心马克……
No, he's okay.
不，他没事。
This is Charlie. Whoa.
这是查理。 哇。
And you gotta watch out for Barry, okay?
你得小心巴里，好吗？
- It's just playing, I'm tellin' ya! - But you could get killed!
- 这只是在玩，我告诉你！  - 但你可能会被杀！
The cats got a little excited, that's all.
猫有点兴奋，仅此而已。
[Mativo] Are you okay? You're crazy!
[Mativo] 你还好吗？ 你疯了！
Oh Mativo, there's Robbie. You've never met Robbie...
哦，马蒂沃，还有罗比。 你从未见过罗比...
He's always out guarding his borders in the daytime.
白天他总是在外面守卫他的边界。
And you're always too afraid to come and visit me at night...
而你总是太害怕晚上来拜访我......
You know, he is the nicest cat in the world.
你知道，他是世界上最好的猫。
And he's also the top cat here.
而且他也是这里的顶级猫。
No, he's the boss, I work for him.
不，他是老板，我为他工作。
Hey Rob, Wauw Wauw.. Well come here.
嘿，Rob，Wauw Wauw .. 来这里。
I want you to meet Mativo.
我想让你见见 Mativo。
See, actually it's Robbie I'm worried about...
看，其实我担心的是罗比……
Their whole life is eh... based on dominance...
他们的一生都是呃……基于统治……
That why we have such a great harmony here.
这就是为什么我们在这里有如此大的和谐。
Because Robbie is such a gentle and loving ruler.
因为罗比是一个如此温柔而充满爱心的统治者。
He also knows he has to protect the others from outsiders...
他也知道他必须保护其他人免受外人的伤害……
Right now he's very worried about Togar.
现在他很担心托加尔。
He's also worried that if the others see that he's worried or afraid...
他也很担心，如果别人看到他担心或者害怕……
That then they start challenging him, like they've been each other all day.
然后他们开始挑战他，就像他们整天在一起一样。
No matter how afraid he is at this moment...
不管他此刻有多害怕……
He still knows he has to see this through.
他仍然知道他必须看透这一切。
The whole meaning of life is before him, Mativo.
生命的全部意义就在他面前，马蒂沃。
- That's why you have to help me. - Help what?
- 这就是为什么你必须帮助我。  - 帮助什么？
- Why? - Because I have to help him, Mativo.
- 为什么？  - 因为我必须帮助他，马蒂沃。
And he could get killed!
而且他可能会被杀！
Don't worry, I'm gonna help you.
别担心，我来帮你。
I .. I don't think you should count on me...
我.. 我不认为你应该指望我......
But only yesterday they were so happy.
但就在昨天，他们还是那么开心。
Now look at them.
现在看看他们。
Finally on the verge of finding paradise
终于在寻找天堂的边缘
And the only thing lacking is my family...
唯一缺少的是我的家人......
To share it with me and Togar comes in and wrecking it!
与我分享，Togar 进来破坏它！
Here comes trouble. It's the grand committee.
麻烦来了。 这是大委员会。
But Prentis is with them.
但普伦蒂斯和他们在一起。
Listen' my friend, let me talk for you.
听着，我的朋友，让我为你说话。
Good morning everybody
大家早上好
I like to open this meeting by reminding you all...
我想通过提醒大家来开启这次会议......
That eh... Hank's original idea...
那个呃……汉克最初的想法……
Was a comparative study of the great cats of the world.
是对世界上伟大的猫科动物的比较研究。
And while preserving the African cats...
在保护非洲猫的同时……
In their natural habitat, he would raise several cats...
在它们的自然栖息地，他会养几只猫……
..of each species.
..每个物种。
Be they African or otherwise.
无论他们是非洲人还是其他人。
And to become almost like a member of the pride.
并变得几乎像骄傲的一员。
Hey it has stripes. It must be another tiger or a liger.
嘿，它有条纹。 它必须是另一只老虎或狮虎。
The mother is a lioness the father must be a tiger.
妈妈一定是母狮，爸爸一定是老虎。
Say hello to Henry the jaguar would ya?
向美洲虎亨利问好好吗？
Not today!
今天不行！
What are you trying to prove, that you can have lions socializing with people?
你想证明什么，你可以让狮子与人交往？
No, but we can't keep exterminating them.
不，但我们不能继续消灭它们。
We can't keep eliminating their land.
我们不能继续消灭他们的土地。
We can't keep exterminating everything that we fear or that inconveniences us.
我们不能一直消灭我们害怕或给我们带来不便的一切。
Let the Zoos keep them alive.
让动物园让他们活着。
Prentis, your actions aren't necessary.
普伦蒂斯，你的行动没有必要。
The government knows there's a better way.
政府知道有更好的方法。
They're moving the people out of the migration paths.
他们正在将人们从迁移路径中转移出去。
I don't know what kind of person could look in the eyes at 200 elephants
不知道什么样的人会看200头大象的眼睛
And put out those lights ...
并熄灭那些灯...
They'd run franticly and panic...
他们会疯狂地奔跑和恐慌......
Do you think your lions would run in panic?
你认为你的狮子会惊慌失措吗？
Well, you'd better start with me first.
好吧，你最好先从我这里开始。
No, I'll start with the tigers first...
不，我先从老虎开始……
That'll teach you for bringing them to Africa!
那会教你把它们带到非洲！
I gotta go help your uncle's they are killing each other.
我得去帮助你叔叔，他们在自相残杀。
Stop It.. Stop It!!
停止它..停止它！
Togar! Togar!!
托加！ 托加！！
You stay out of it, you let Robbie take care of him.
你远离它，你让罗比照顾他。
Yeah, you guys are smart, you stay out of it.
是的，你们很聪明，你别管它。
Oh great..
哦，太好了..
Hey Tommy, Jimmy Oh you all hiding here
嘿，汤米，吉米，你们都躲在这里
Oh I don't blame ya. All those those guys are fighting.
哦，我不怪你。 那些家伙都在战斗。
That's my Jacket!
那是我的夹克！
Hank!
汉克！
Hank! Hank!
汉克！ 汉克！
Come on go in the house and get some bandages.
来吧，进屋拿些绷带。
No!!
不！！
Oh what the hell's wrong with you, all you got's a few scratches.
哦，你到底怎么了，你只有几个划痕。
You're lucky I told her, I didn't get ya.
你很幸运我告诉她，我没有得到你。
I think you should take a bus.
我觉得你应该坐公共汽车。
It goes right by there..
它就在那里..
Oh no, I think we should wait.
哦不，我想我们应该等一下。
No, if you wait until tonight and he doesn't come...
不，如果你等到今晚他不来……
There's no other bus for 2 days and
there's no place for you to stay here.
- Oh what do we do? - Will he know where to take us?
- 哦，我们怎么办？  - 他会知道带我们去哪里吗？
Hey, she's dry.
嘿，她是干的。
Alice has no milk.
爱丽丝没有牛奶。
Listen, I have to go change.
听着，我得去换衣服了。
- I'll go wait in my boat - okay
- 我会在我的船上等待 - 好的
Oh. Maybe I come with you?
哦。 也许我和你一起去？
- What we do now? - Just stand up to them.
- 我们现在在干什么？  - 站出来反对他们。
Don't let them get away with anything...
不要让他们逍遥法外...
You gotta let them see how strong you are...
你得让他们看看你有多强……
Come on lions we have to clean the house of Madelaine.
来吧狮子，我们必须打扫玛德莱娜的房子。
Come on lions
来吧狮子
Come on Diane come on, go. Come on Patrick..
来吧黛安来吧，走吧。 来吧帕特里克..
Are you sure there aren't anymore big ones in here?
你确定这里没有大人物了吗？
Well, hello Gary.
好吧，你好加里。
Whoa, why didn't you go with ... (roar) Why didn't you go with your friends?
哇，你为什么不和......（咆哮）你为什么不和你的朋友一起去？
Come on, you should go with your friends...
来吧，你应该和你的朋友一起去......
Oh, come on.
哦，来吧。
You really changed this place. New curtains, new drapes..
你真的改变了这个地方。 新窗帘，新窗帘……
New everything!
新的一切！
Come on go with your friends. Wauw, come on.
快和你的朋友一起去吧。 哇，来吧。
Oh yes, ??? Goodbye.
哦是的， ？？？ 再见。
Come on..
来吧..
Why, don't worry baby, Robbie can handle Togar.
为什么，宝贝别担心，罗比可以对付托加。
Your father is tougher than you think!
你爸爸比你想象的要坚强！
Wauw.. Oh come on you're hurt my hand.
Wauw.. 哦，拜托你伤到我的手了。
See, my hand hurt.
看，我的手受伤了。
Come on! Come on baby.
来吧！ 来吧宝贝。
Wauw!
哇！
I've seen that rogue Togar as far away as 200 miles.
我在 200 英里外看到了那个流氓托加尔。
This is the first time he's come in.
这是他第一次进来。
I have a hunch that Robbie and Togar could be brothers.
我有一种预感，Robbie 和 Togar 可能是兄弟。
You know Bugsy and Robbie we're both rogue lions.
你知道巴格西和罗比我们都是流氓狮子。
I found them dying from battle wounds
我发现他们死于战伤
Now if Togar were sick or dying...
现在，如果 Togar 生病或快死了……
These guys would probably except him
这些人可能除了他
- But the way he is now... - ??? arrived.
- 但他现在的样子... - ？？？ 到达的。
But he can't help that. As a loner he's too slow to catch his normal diner.
但他无能为力。 作为一个孤独的人，他太慢了，无法赶上正常的晚餐。
And the hungrier he gets, the more desperate he'll get.
他越饿，就越绝望。
And the more desperate he gets, the more ferocious he gets.
而他越是绝望，就越是凶残。
Because the only way he can eat most of the time...
因为他大部分时间唯一能吃的东西……
Is by taking his meals from whole prides alliance.
是通过从整个骄傲联盟中拿走他的饭菜。
You've got to be pretty ferocious to do that!
你必须非常凶猛才能做到这一点！
Sooner or later he's gonna get killed.
迟早要被打死。
Come on, Gary!
来吧，加里！
♪ Why'd I ever leave Madelaine alone ♪ ♪ Make me believe, you'll never leave ♪
♪ 为什么我要让玛德琳独自一人 ♪ ♪ 让我相信，你永远不会离开 ♪
♪ It couldn't hurt to pretend ♪ ♪ Why'd I ever leave Madelaine alone ♪
♪ 假装不会有什么坏处 ♪ ♪ 为什么我要让玛德琳一个人 ♪
Billie!
比利！
Whoa, don't try touching me!
哇，不要试图碰我！
Leave that alone!
别管它！
That's my Jacket...
那是我的夹克...
Give me that..
给我那个..
Hey Hank, come and help me.
嘿汉克，过来帮帮我。
Give my jacket! That's my jacket..
给我的夹克！ 那是我的夹克。。
Help! Help!
帮助！ 帮助！
- They almost killed me - You know you're not supposed to run.
- 他们差点杀了我 - 你知道你不应该跑。
My head knew it, but my feet didn't.
我的头知道，但我的脚不知道。
Oh, hi babe. Oh...
哦，你好宝贝。 哦...
- Putt them out! - They're trying to stay away from Togar.
- 把他们赶出去！  - 他们正试图远离托加尔。
- Come on. - Why'd they have to be in here?
- 来吧。  - 他们为什么要在这里？
Why this open-door policy you have in here, anyway?
无论如何，为什么你在这里有这个门户开放政策？
All the doors are closed except for here..
除了这里，所有的门都关上了。。
And the bathroom
还有浴室
There's nothing they can tear up here or the bathroom.
他们在这里或浴室没有任何东西可以撕毁。
- Putt them out! - Mativo, this is their home!
- 把他们赶出去！  - Mativo，这是他们的家！
What do you think you're running, a country club for lions?
你认为你在跑什么，狮子的乡村俱乐部？
Come on, sit down here...
来，坐这里……
Sit down, you're okay!
坐下，你没事！
Sit down. You're okay. Sit down.
坐下。 你没事。 坐下。
Hey, no more fighting!
嘿，别再吵架了！
Come here. Oooh, sit down you're okay.
过来。 哦，坐下你没事。
These stupid lions are frightening me.
这些愚蠢的狮子让我害怕。
And you're going to bring Madelaine and the children to this?
你要把玛德莱娜和孩子们带到这里吗？
This would be great for them
这对他们来说会很棒
Not boxed in, like back in Chicago.
没有装箱，就像回到芝加哥一样。
Hey, wait a minute...
嘿，等一下...
I just thought he had a cataract start.
我只是以为他有白内障开始。
Oh, That's Billy he's great
哦，那是比利，他很棒
They're right. You must be on something
他们是对的。 你一定在做某事
I couldn't last a day. You expect her to sleep with the lions, are you?
我坚持不了一天。 你希望她和狮子睡觉，是吗？
What do you care if I sleep with my wife?
如果我和我的妻子上床，你在乎什么？
Mom, do you know that a man can have as many wives as he wants to, here?
妈妈，你知道吗，一个男人可以娶多少个老婆，在这里？
And what does that supposed to mean?
那是什么意思？
I mean, how could you be away from dad for so long?
我的意思是，你怎么能离开爸爸这么久？
You know that your father and I were having problems
你知道你父亲和我有问题
And we thought it would be better to be apart for a while.
我们认为分开一段时间会更好。
You know absence makes the heart grow fonder.
你知道缺席会让心变得更爱。
The heart maybe, but what about the sex glands?
也许是心脏，但性腺呢？
Sex is all you think about lately young lady...
性是你最近想到的所有年轻女士......
You'd better watch it. You're gonna get your little tail in trouble.
你最好看一下。 你会给你的小尾巴惹上麻烦。
Someday I hope you'll understand the beauty of restraint and self-denial.
我希望有一天你会明白克制和克己的美。
Well, I hope it wasn't restraint and self-denial that drove dad away...
好吧，我希望把爸爸赶走的不是克制和克己……
♪ ... Isn't it time that we stop ♪
♪...我们是不是该停下来了♪
Hey Mativo, you know what my kids used to do every time I started to sing?
嘿 Mativo，你知道我的孩子每次开始唱歌时都做什么吗？
They'd hold their hands over their ears...
他们会用手捂住耳朵……
And say oh no! Or they turn on a radio.
说哦不！ 或者他们打开收音机。
Hey Hank. Don't let them in the boat
嘿汉克。 不要让他们上船
You're crazy!
你疯了！
I think, he said it's just over the hill.
我想，他说就在山那边。
♪ You will never guess ♪ ♪ how many dreams I dreamed about ♪
♪ 你永远猜不到 ♪ ♪ 我做了多少梦 ♪
♪ or just how empty they all seem without her ♪
♪ 或者没有她，他们看起来多么空虚 ♪
♪  soooo kiss me once kiss me twice ♪
♪ 吻我一次 吻我两次 ♪
♪ and kiss me once again ♪
♪ 再吻我一次 ♪
♪ It's been a long ... ♪
♪ 好久不见…… ♪
I can't steer.
我无法驾驶。
I think were sinking.
我认为正在下沉。
Abandon ship!
弃船！
Hey Mativo...
嘿马蒂沃...
Hey Mativo climb out over that way.
嘿 Mativo 从那边爬出来。
Don't swim, they'll get you.
不要游泳，他们会抓住你的。
Mom, come here look...
妈妈，过来看看...
It's fantastic!
太棒了！
Yeah, Dad! Hey Dad!
是的，爸爸！ 嘿老爸！
Dad?
爸爸？
Hank?
汉克？
Hello?
你好？
Hank?
汉克？
Dad?
爸爸？
We're here...
我们在这儿...
Dad?
爸爸？
Oh dear...
哦亲爱的...
Hey Dad??
嘿老爸？？
Hank?
汉克？
- This is really a nice place. - Come on up this place is really wild.
- 这真是个好地方。  - 来吧，这个地方真的很狂野。
Oh, I'll give anything for some sleep.
哦，我会为了睡觉而付出任何代价。
Oh, I don't understand...
哦，我不明白...
Is that a tarantula?
这是狼蛛吗？
- You simple-minded jerk! - Stop that!
- 你这个头脑简单的混蛋！  - 停下！
Oh my God!
我的天啊！
Where could he be?
他会在哪里？
Jerry, run it up at all the windows
杰瑞，在所有窗户上运行它
Then we will dust everything and surprise your father.
然后我们会把一切都抹去，让你父亲大吃一惊。
Hey a motorcycle.
嘿摩托车。
I saw a thing, I think it was a pelican.
我看到了一个东西，我认为它是一只鹈鹕。
it's a Kawasaki!
它是川崎！
Holy mackerel! Look at that...
神圣的鲭鱼！ 看那个...
I don't believe what I'm seeing
我不相信我所看到的
Those can't be Dad's lions.
那些不可能是爸爸的狮子。
Oh God, look what the cat dragged in!
哦，上帝，看看猫拖进来的东西！
Melanie? Mom, get in here...
梅兰妮？ 妈妈，进来...
Get in here.
进来。
Jerry? John!
杰瑞？ 约翰！
- Where's Mom and Mel? - They're downstairs, come on...
- 妈妈和梅尔在哪里？  - 他们在楼下，快点...
What the heck is going on down there.
下面到底发生了什么。
- Alright we got trouble. - Where they all come from?
- 好吧，我们遇到了麻烦。  - 他们都是从哪里来的？
Nice lion. Nice lion!
好狮子。 好狮子！
Oh.
哦。
- Now honey you alright? - Yeah, but I'm scared mom.
- 现在亲爱的你好吗？  - 是的，但我很害怕妈妈。
Oh, I know honey so am I
哦，我知道亲爱的，我也是
Oh, honey stay here, I will get the boys.
哦，亲爱的，留在这里，我会得到男孩们的。
- Help - John?
- 帮助 - 约翰？
I'm in here.
我在这里。
John, you are alright?
约翰，你还好吗？
Where is Jerry?
杰瑞在哪里？
Help! Help!
帮助！ 帮助！
Jerry.. Jerry?
杰瑞..杰瑞？
Oh god.
天啊。
- Are you alright? - You could have suffocated!
- 你还好吗？  - 你可能已经窒息了！
- You could've died, dummy. - Shut up I almost died.
- 你本可以死的，笨蛋。  - 闭嘴我差点死了。
What kind of jerk would hide himself in an icebox?
什么样的混蛋会把自己藏在冰箱里？
Get me outta here!
给我滚出去！
Help, mom! John!
帮助，妈妈！ 约翰！
Jerry!?
杰瑞！？
- Get me outta here. - Come on, one - two - three.
- 带我离开这里。  - 来吧，一 - 二 - 三。
Maybe there's some guns around here. We gotta find a gun...
也许这附近有一些枪。 我们得找把枪...
I think we have to split while we can.
我认为我们必须尽可能分开。
Yeah, sure with eight-thousand lions and tigers outside...
是的，外面有八千只狮子和老虎……
Well, if we stay here we'll end up being eaten alive.
好吧，如果我们留在这里，我们最终会被活生生地吃掉。
We're not going to get eaten.
我们不会被吃掉。
When dad gets here he'll show us how to handle them.
等爸爸到了，他会教我们如何处理它们。
Until then we just board up the windows.
在那之前，我们只是用木板把窗户封起来。
- Wait a minute who voted you in? - I did.
- 等一下，谁给你投票的？  - 我做到了。
I suppose you want to make a run for it?
我想你想为它奔波？
Right, I'll take the motorcycle and go get help.
好的，我会骑着摩托车去寻求帮助。
I know bikes and I know the road we came in on.
我知道自行车，我知道我们走过的路。
That's not gonna help, that's letting you escape and leaving us here.
这无济于事，那是让你逃跑，把我们留在这儿。
Give me your handkerchief, John.
把你的手帕给我，约翰。
Oh, I wanna go home.
哦，我想回家。
Madelaine is gonna kill me.
玛德莱娜要杀了我。
It'll go much faster faster if you go up there and borrow some bicycles.
如果你去那里借一些自行车，它会走得更快。
- Okay! - I'll take the tigers out.
- 好的！  - 我会带老虎出去。
Go around the back of the village.
在村子后面转一圈。
(Mativo speaks the local language explains tigers are passing the village)
（马蒂沃会说当地语言，解释老虎正在经过村庄）
Don't tell me he said ...  you said
不要告诉我他说...你说
I'm not interested in your bitterness.
我对你的苦涩不感兴趣。
Who asked you to go over there?
谁叫你过去的？
I can go on any property to kill animals that I deem are a danger to human lives.
我可以在任何财产上杀死我认为对人类生命构成危险的动物。
Don't tell me you care about his family!
不要告诉我你关心他的家人！
I'm telling you there'll be no culling of cats,
我告诉你不会扑杀猫，
elephants or any animal ever again.
大象或任何动物再次出现。
Well, you should've been at that madhouse and seen those cats this morning.
好吧，你今天早上应该去疯人院看看那些猫。
I don't care what you've seen.
我不在乎你看到了什么。
You're not going to go out there and slaughtering animals.
你不会去那里屠宰动物。
Recall elephants if there are so many
如果有这么多，请召回大象
Prentis, you're completely out of line.
Prentis，你完全不合时宜。
you are not going to kill those cats.
你不会杀死那些猫。
You can tell me what you're gonna do...
你可以告诉我你要做什么...
And you can tell me what the rest of this committee is gonna do, Rick.
你可以告诉我这个委员会的其他成员会做什么，瑞克。
But I'll be damned if you're gonna tell me what I'm gonna do.
但如果你要告诉我我要做什么，我会被诅咒的。
- We can't escort 2 tigers. - Well, I try to make them go home.
- 我们不能护送 2 只老虎。  - 好吧，我试着让他们回家。
How come they're not doing what you're telling them?
为什么他们不做你告诉他们的事情？
Well, they're not trained cats they're just friends.
好吧，它们不是受过训练的猫，它们只是朋友。
Stay off my path...
别走我的路...
Come on, where you're going? Come on down.
来吧，你要去哪里？ 下来吧。
You go, I'm not going.
你去，我不去。
You know, you're right.
你知道，你是对的。
I can't go to the airport with them, they'd go right in with me.
我不能和他们一起去机场，他们会和我一起进去。
Hey, I got an idea for ya...
嘿，我给你一个主意……
Hang down off that branch, let your feet hang down here...
从那根树枝上垂下来，让你的脚在这里垂下……
What?
什么？
Kick your feet they'll jump right up and try to get ya and they'll stay here.
踢你的脚，他们会马上跳起来，试图抓住你，他们会留在这里。
- I can sneak away. - No no, I'll not doing that.
- 我可以偷偷溜走。  - 不不，我不会那样做。
Listen ...
听...
Take your shirt off, okay?
脱掉你的衬衫，好吗？
And dangle it down.
把它挂下来。
Hold it by the sleeve.
抓住它的袖子。
There you go.
你去吧。
Hurry back!
快回来！
♪ You make me feel so alive ♪ ♪ make me feel like living on and on ♪
♪ 你让我感觉如此充满活力 ♪ ♪ 让我感觉像活下去 ♪
♪ You make me feel so alive ♪ ♪ there's more to life ♪
♪ 你让我感觉如此充满活力 ♪ ♪ 生命还有更多 ♪
♪ There's so much more to life than meets the eye ♪
♪ 生活远不止眼前一亮 ♪
♪ It takes a lot to see, the forest for the trees ♪
♪ 见多识广，只见树木 ♪
♪ You make me feel so alive! ♪ ♪ And I thank you all for showing why ♪
♪ 你让我感觉如此有活力！  ♪ ♪ 我感谢你们展示为什么 ♪
♪ There's more to life than meets the eye ♪
♪ 生活远不止眼前一亮 ♪
Why did you bring us here? We're just gonna die!
你为什么带我们来这里？ 我们就要死了！
No, we are not going to die!
不，我们不会死！
Your father's gonna be here soon and it'll be all over.
你父亲很快就会来，一切都会过去的。
Well, why isn't he here now, he knew we were coming?
好吧，他现在为什么不在这里，他知道我们要来？
You can bellyache all you want about him staying away
你可以随心所欲地让他远离
but if he isn't here it's because he's dead
但如果他不在这里，那是因为他死了
and he's not coming, I know it.
他不会来，我知道。
Boy I've been waiting to do this for a long time.
男孩，我已经等了很长时间了。
Don't you think we should wait?
你不认为我们应该等待吗？
We shouldn't allow anything smaller than a 30.6 for Lions.
对于 Lions，我们不应该允许任何小于 30.6 的值。
Have you seen my wife and children?
你看到我的妻子和孩子了吗？
No, I didn't see them
不，我没有看到他们
I saw a lady and three children.
我看到一位女士和三个孩子。
I told them to catch the bus.
我告诉他们赶公共汽车。
What time?
什么时候？
It was just about 10:30.
时间刚好是10:30左右。
Let me borrow your car.
让我借你的车。
No, I don't have a car.
不，我没有车。
Leonard?
伦纳德？
Oh Leonard... Leonard ... Leonard.
哦伦纳德……伦纳德……伦纳德。
Okay..
好的..
(Leonard gives Hank instructions in their local language)
（伦纳德用当地语言给汉克指示）
Come on putt your bike in the truck.
来吧，把你的自行车放在卡车上。
They must be in the house already, they took the bus yesterday.
他们肯定已经在屋子里了，他们昨天坐了公共汽车。
Nikki get in the car. Come on get in back.
尼基上车。 快点回去吧。
Come on Craig get in with us Come on Craig that's a good boy.
来吧克雷格和我们一起来吧克雷格是个好孩子。
Yeah, it's a good boy, turn around.
是的，是个好孩子，转身。
He's trying to close me in the trunk!
他想把我关在后备箱里！
Hey, come on get in...
嘿，进来吧……
Hey, well.. come on. Get in!
嘿，好吧……来吧。 进来！
You're crazy, with them in the back? They'll bite my head off.
你疯了，跟他们在后面？ 他们会咬掉我的头。
Either get in or walk, cause I'm going...
要么进去要么走，因为我要去...
Make them walk! Hank, this is madness.
让他们走路！ 汉克，这太疯狂了。
If somebody sees them this far from my place, they'll shoot them.
如果有人在离我家这么远的地方看到他们，他们就会开枪打死他们。
Don't fool yourself! These are your friends, huh?
别自欺欺人了！ 这些是你的朋友吧？
And do you know what your friends up over are doing to your family right now?
你知道你的朋友现在对你的家人做了什么吗？
they are making diner of them.
他们正在做晚餐。
- They're eating them! - Mativo, shut up!
- 他们正在吃它们！  - 马蒂沃，闭嘴！
They're sitting around eating them cracking their bones...
他们坐在周围吃着他们的骨头……
- Shut up! - They're licking their bones clean.
- 闭嘴！  - 他们正在把骨头舔干净。
Shut up!
闭嘴！
- Who are you? - Come on!
- 你是谁？  - 来吧！
- Hey, don't go so fast it's too bumpy. - I have to Mativo.
- 嘿，别走那么快太颠簸了。  - 我必须到马蒂沃。
By the way
顺便一提
Do they know that they should not run?
他们知道不应该跑吗？
You should've sent them a list of rules and regulations before they came.
你应该在他们来之前给他们发一份规章制度清单。
Argh, poor Leonard's...
啊，可怜的伦纳德……
Let's get out of here.
我们离开这里吧。
I think Melanie was right. Let's go take the boat.
我认为梅兰妮是对的。 我们乘船去吧。
Jerry, you go first, go ahead.
杰瑞，你先走，继续。
Jerry, you're rowing the wrong way...
杰瑞，你划错了方向……
Boy that was close..
那个接近的男孩..
Get away! Get away from me!
逃离！ 离我远点！
Help me! Help me!
帮我！ 帮我！
Oh, less than 10 miles to go and we're stuck!
哦，还有不到 10 英里的路程，我们被困住了！
- What's wrong? - The jack wont wont in the sand..
- 怎么了？  - 千斤顶不会在沙子里..
And the more I dig the more the car slides...
我挖得越多，汽车滑得越多……
- Then I'll have to run. - But you know you're not supposed to run.
- 那我就得跑了。  - 但你知道你不应该跑。
You hold the Tigers back would you? So that they don't tackle me.
你能阻止老虎队吗？ 以免他们对付我。
- What? - Just use this...
- 什么？  - 就用这个...
Use this! Look like that..
用这个！ 那样看。。
Hey, Prentis, did you see that? I got him right in the neck.
嘿，Prentis，你看到了吗？ 我抓住了他的脖子。
Sooner or later the lions are gonna get us
狮子迟早会得到我们
I'm gonna go for help.
我要去寻求帮助。
Okay, let's go see if the other doors in the house are secure.
好的，我们去看看房子里的其他门是否安全。
- John! - I'm gonna get help.
- 约翰！  - 我会得到帮助。
- And leave us here? - I tell you it's suicide...
- 把我们留在这里？  - 我告诉你这是自杀...
Good luck, son!
祝你好运，儿子！
Oh no...
不好了...
Ah, get out here...
啊，滚出去……
Open the door! Come on!
开门！ 来吧！
Go on, get out of here! Leave it, go on, leave it!
走吧，离开这里！ 离开它，继续，离开它！
- Jerry, open the door! Come on. - You think I'm crazy?
- 杰瑞，开门！ 来吧。  - 你觉得我疯了吗？
What kinda jerk would go off the roof on a motorcycle?
什么样的混蛋会骑摩托车从屋顶上跳下来？
Get off of her!
滚开她！
Hey what are you doing on the floor?
嘿，你在地上做什么？
John, I can't get my leg out.
约翰，我的腿抬不出来。
Come on help her, I hold 'm. I hold 'm.
快来帮帮她吧，我抱住她。 我抱着我。
Melanie come here...
梅兰妮过来...
Oh. O my goodness!
哦。 我的天啊！
- Jerry help your sister. - He just trying to kiss her.
- 杰瑞帮助你的妹妹。  - 他只是想吻她。
Do it, open the door!
做吧，开门！
You think we have enough ammunition?
你认为我们有足够的弹药吗？
I've got plenty in this belt and thirty in the other.
我在这条腰带上有很多东西，在另一条腰带上有三十个。
Remember where all the cheetahs, leopards and tiger drop..
记住所有猎豹、豹子和老虎的落脚点。
We skin them on the way back.
我们在回来的路上剥皮。
The Lions are worthless, leave them for the hyena's
狮子一文不值，把它们留给鬣狗吧
Mom, go over the tread...
妈妈，越过踏板...
Come on Mom...
来吧妈妈...
See mom, there's another house. It's completely safe
妈妈，还有另一所房子。 这是完全安全的
That's a good thing because I can't walk another step.
这是一件好事，因为我不能再走一步了。
I'm so tired, my legs just buckle under me
我太累了，我的腿只是在我下面弯曲
I just have to sleep for a while...
我只需要睡一会儿...
Oh Donny lion...
哦唐尼狮子...
Oh Donny...
哦唐尼...
Come on my friend, get up! I'll make sure they are ???
来吧，我的朋友，起来！ 我会确保他们是？？？
Togar get away!!
托加滚开！！
Oh you... poor stupid jerks!
哦，你……可怜的愚蠢的混蛋！
Togar, get away...
托加，走开……
Let's try to get them outside.
让我们试着让他们出去。
I do not think they are trying to hurt us at all.
我认为他们根本没有试图伤害我们。
Melanie, John get away from those lions.
梅兰妮，约翰远离那些狮子。
Mom, if they wanted to get us they would have done while we were asleep.
妈妈，如果他们想得到我们，他们会在我们睡觉的时候做的。
Make sure that his mother is not around.
确保他的母亲不在。
They are really friendly.
他们真的很友好。
Oh she's beautiful, isn't she?
哦，她很漂亮，不是吗？
They're really friendly.
他们真的很友好。
Togar! Togar!!
托加！ 托加！！
Madelaine!
玛德莱娜！
John!
约翰！
Hello Lion
你好狮子
Togar! ... Togar! ... Togar!!
托加！  ……托加！  ……托加！！
Madelaine!
玛德莱娜！
Hey you guys stay away for a while..
嘿，你们别走开。。
Hey, kids how are ya?
嘿，孩子们，你们好吗？
Wauw oh...oh ...oh
哇哦...哦...哦
I better go help your mom.
我最好去帮助你妈妈。
Hey, Lynn get off. Come on get up.
嘿，林恩下车。 快起来吧。
Don't hit her Jerry, hug her she wants you to hold her.
不要打她杰瑞，拥抱她，她想让你抱她。
Are you okay. I'm so happy you're here.
你还好吗。 我很高兴你在这里。
You're okay don't worry.
你没事别担心。
- Don't worry! - Oh...
- 不要担心！  - 哦...
Oh, I sure love you. Oh I love you too!
哦，我肯定爱你。 哦，我也爱你！
Hey... Listen don't say anything about Prentis okay?
嘿... 听着别说什么关于Prentis好吗？
But he was killing our lions
但他正在杀死我们的狮子
I don't want you to say anything about that either.
我也不希望你对此说什么。
It will spoil the reunion. I will tell them later.
它会破坏团聚。 我稍后会告诉他们。
Listen, I want you to meet my family. This is my wife Madelaine.
听着，我想让你见见我的家人。 这是我的妻子玛德琳。
This my son John.
这是我的儿子约翰。
This is my daughter Melanie. Melanie.. Mativo.
这是我的女儿梅兰妮。 梅兰妮.. 马蒂沃。
My son Jerry. Come on this way.
我的儿子杰瑞。 这边来。
Listen, I have a surprise for you. Why? We are glad to see you.
听着，我有一个惊喜要给你。 为什么？ 我们很高兴见到你。
Whaddya all do wearing my clothes?
什么都穿我的衣服？
Oh No, what happened?
哦不，怎么了？
Get back, they're lively and they all want to meet you.
回去吧，他们很活泼，都想认识你。
We already met them...
我们已经见过他们了...
Isn't this fantastic!
这不是太棒了！
What do ya think, you guys gonna stay a while?
你们觉得怎么样，你们会留下来吗？
Sure dad. I don't have to be back in Chicago before next week.
当然是爸爸 我不必在下周之前回到芝加哥。
(Robert Hawk Florczak - Here We Are In Eden)
（罗伯特霍克 Florczak - 我们在伊甸园）